Guide to the Jarvis-Robinson Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Jarvis-Robinson Family Papers
1740-1963
1830-1920
WA MSS S-2948
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
13.67
(34 boxes)
Correspondence, diaries, printed material, business papers, personal papers, photographs, postcards, and maps relating to Samuel Colt and the Jarvis-Robinson family.
Jarvis family
Colt, Samuel, 1814-1862
Robinson family
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Jarvis-Robinson Family
The Jarvis-Robinson family comprised relatives of Samuel Colt, including his wife, Elizabeth Hart Jarvis Colt (1826-1905), her brother and Colt's business partner, Richard Jarvis (1829-1903), and her sister, Hetty Hart Jarvis (1828-1898). Their descendants included Elizabeth Hart Jarvis Beach Robinson (1869-1936) and her husband, Charles Leonard Frost Robinson (1874-1916).
Samuel Colt (1814-1862)
Samuel Colt, inventor, industrialist, and arms manufacturer.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, diaries, printed material, business papers, personal papers, photographs, postcards, and maps relating to Samuel Colt and the Jarvis-Robinson family. Colt's business activities, correspondence from the Jarvis-Robinson family, and printed ephemera relating to Colt's Manufacturing Company and the family's social engagements are especially well represented in the papers. Colt's national and international business ventures, particularly with Texas and Russia; family travel diaries; and an 1868 map of Hartford are also present.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: Samuel Colt Acquisition and Jarvis-Robinson Family Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection was acquired in two discrete increments. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with material found in other acquisitions. For instance, materials pertaining to Samuel Colt can be found in both groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Samuel Colt Acquisition was purchased from Elizabeth C. Titus Putnam on Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2006. The Jarvis-Robinson Family Acquisition was a gift of Elizabeth C. Titus Putnam, 2006
Colt firearms; Weapons industry -- United States; Weapons industry -- Russia; Firearms industry and trade -- United States; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona; Mines and mineral resources -- Mexico; Russia -- Commerce -- United States; United States -- Commerce -- Russia; Connecticut -- Economic conditions -- 19th century; Connecticut -- Social life and customs; Hartford (Conn.) -- Maps; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Jarvis family; Robinson family; Colt's Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Co
- Samuel Colt Acquisition
  - Colt automatic gun (model 1914) pamphlet (Box 1)
  - Samuel Colt journal containing record of receipts and recipe for chemical preparations, 1831-1845 (Box 1)
  - List of Colt patents, 1849-1858 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Colt correspondence, 1848-1861, undated; 18 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Colt Manufacturing and Firearms agreement in pursuance of claim against Republic of Texas, 1850 November 16 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Colt legal papers appointing John M. Gould power of attorney for "Patent Arms Manufacturing Co.", 1850 April (Box 1)
  - Colt Patent and Firearm Manufacturing correspondence, 1851 (Box 1)
  - J. Peard letter to Charles Manby regarding Colt Firearm sales, 1852 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Colt, Manufacturing and Firearms dispute with Col. Porter of Hartford, CT, 1852-1857; 2 (Box 1)
  - Charles Deunet letters regarding purchase of Colt revolving pistol, 1852 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Colt passports, American, Russian, and Western European, 1854 (Box 1)
  - Samuel Colt correspondence from Prince Dolgoransky, Russian Minister of War, 1854 (Box 1)
  - Letters of introduction from Charles Manby, 1854 (Box 1)
  - Copy of Patent for Improvements in manufacture of cartridges, 1855 December 8 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence contract list of arms relating to Colt's sale of firearms to Russia, 1855-1857 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, Russian letters, 1855-1869 (Box 2)
  - Draft of letter to Russia Ambassador regarding arms sales and introduction of Colt's brother, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Letter to Baron Stoeckl, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Pass to inspect Tula imperial arms manufactury, 1856 September (Box 2)
  - Bank note, signed, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Power of attorney to Richard D. Hubbard, 1856 June 3 (Box 2)
  - Letter of regret to Grand Duke Michel Nicolaevitch, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence predominantly with Seymour regarding attire and lodging while in Moscow, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Ephemera relating to trip to Russia, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Ordres de Suites de Fetes invitation, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Colt request for interviews and replies, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Permissions to travel: Colt's and Jarvis', 1856 (Box 2)
  - Invitation to visit Prince Esterhazy, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Diplomatic core list Russia, 1856 (Box 2)
  - Jarvis, Hetty Hart correspondence from St. Petersburg, 1856; 2 (Box 2)
  - Samuel Colt invitation while in Russia to meet with various dignitaries, 1856-1857 (Box 2)
  - Letters regarding Colt firearm business, 1857 (Box 2)
  - Colt Patent and Firearm Manufacture, Hartford Evening Press article regarding lawsuit, 1857 (Box 2)
  - Letter from Sam Houston, 1857 (Box 2)
  - Lamar property taxes, deeds and papers, 1858-1861; 2 (Box 2)
  - Samuel Colt correspondence concerning Lamar, TX, 1857-1858; 2 (Box 2)
  - Samuel Colt correspondence (predominantly with Jarvis concerning holdings in Western United States), 1858-1859 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, correspondence from C. Macon Thompson, 1858 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, letters of agreement on payment schedule between Colt and B.R. Floyd regarding York coal lands, 1858-1859 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt correspondence to Col. S. P. Sargent, Colt Firearms, 1858 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, correspondence from Baron Stueckl, 1858 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, power of attorney to R.W.H. Jarvis, 1858 (Box 3)
  - Colt's Patent Fire Arms Manufacturing Co., price list, 1858 January 1 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt private correspondence with Richard Jarvis regarding Colt holdings in Western United States, 1859; 2 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, copy of letter from Pawarendrramesr (Pinklao, King of Siam, 1808-1865), second king of Siam regarding gift of vase, 1860 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, contract between Colt and Sam Cooley for East Hartford property known as "The Henrey", 1860 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt estate, 1863-1972; 3 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, Sonora Exploring and Mining Co., correspondence regarding stock exchange and payment dispute, 1860-1863 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, bills of exchange, 1860 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, letter from Alden to Capt. General Don Francisco Serrano, Superior Governor of Cuba, 1861 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt correspondence from Allen and Hale (Galveston, TX), 1861 October 3 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, "In Memoriam", 1862 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, family genealogy and financial records, 1862-1866 (Box 3)
  - Colt Patent Firearms Manufacturing invoice for arms, 1862 (Box 3)
  - Colt Patent and Firearms Manufacturing correspondence, 1864 (Box 3)
  - Colt Manufacturing and Firearms cash balance statement, 1865 (Box 3)
  - Colt Patent Firearms Manufacturing correspondence, 1865 (Box 3)
  - Colt Manufacturing and Firearms balance sheet, 1866 (Box 3)
  - Colt Patent and Manufacturing, 1868 (Box 3)
  - Colt Patent Firearms Manufacturing correspondence, 1869 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, cheques, 1869-1870 (Box 3)
  - Colt Patent and Firearms Manufacturing correspondence between R.W. Jarvis and W. B. Franklin regarding sale of arms to Russia, 1869-1872 (Box 3)
  - Colt Manufacturing and Firearms cash balance statement, 1870 (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, American Institute, pencil draft, undated (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt, guardianship of Isabella Colt, undated (Box 3)
  - Colt Patent and Firearms Manufacturing, 1879-1880 (Box 3)
  - Colt Patent Arms Manufacturing Co., list of stockholders, 1887 August (Box 3)
  - Samuel Colt letter of introduction, John C. Calhoun to Ordinance Division of War Dept., 1836 (Box 3)
  - Sam Colt, correspondence from Hiram Powers, 1851, 1866 (Box 3)
  - Vallecillo Silver Mining Co., notice to stockholders, 1859 September 6 (Box 3)
  - Connecticut Historical Society, 1857-1880 (Box 3)
  - Christopher Colt, Jr. correspondence to Sam Colt regarding debt, 1848-1851 (Box 3)
  - J.T. Lally letter describing situation in Arizona mines to R.W. Jarvis, 1862 (Box 3)
  - Richard Jarvis itineraries, 1859 (Box 3)
  - William Jarvis tax bills, 1852-1853, 1861 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1857 (Box 3)
- Jarvis-Robinson Family Acquisition
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, financial papers, printed material, and personal papers, including a journal, by or relating to Samuel Colt.
  - "Family Correspondence" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "correspondence regarding Newington House" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "Living Flag" and "Gold Star Mother" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "newspaper clippings (Asst.)" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "Pamphlet: Early Silversmiths of CT" (Box 4)
  - "3 letters to Mrs. Robinson regarding Joseph Krehs" (Box 4)
  - "Mrs. C.L.F. Robinson Letter to Editor of St. Nicholas regarding poem "The Secret" plagiarism (Box 4)
    - "Copies" (Asst.) of originals to Elizabeth H.J.B. Robinson (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "list of objects loaned to Wadsworth Atheneum" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "Correspondence regarding loss of her son, C.C. Robinson" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "Gold Star Medallion" and "Pilgrimage" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "records of silver purchases" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "assorted ephemera" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "receipts, visa, and other ephemera" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "Instructions regarding estate from Elizabeth HJ Colt", 1905 (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth H.J.B. "letters from Charles E. Gross regarding estate of EJ Colt", 1905-1915 (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Elizabeth J "Fund Disbursement by E.J. Cushman", 1936 (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Fanny De Groot correspondence (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Francis "(C.W.) correspondence" (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Francis, 1814-1885 (Box 4)
  - Robinson, Frank Tracey, 1847-1896 (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Frank Tracey "concerning 80 Madison Ave. NYC" (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Ida M. Frost (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Henry De Groot (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Robert McCarter, 1852-1895 (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Ruth Allerton Stone (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Thomas H., 1928 (Box 5)
  - Robinson, Thomas Hastings will and testament, 1918 (Box 5)
  - Sanders, John (Schenectady/Scotia NY) correspondence (Box 5)
  - Schley, W.S. "Autograph" (Box 5)
  - Scudder, Horace (Box 5)
  - Seabury, Samuel, 1868 (Box 5)
  - Sheffield, Amelia Hart, 1830-1906 (Box 5)
  - Sickles, D.E. to August Belmont "Introducing Sam Colt", 1853 (Box 5)
  - Sigourney, L.H. to Elizabeth Colt (Box 5)
  - Sigourney, Lydia to Elizabeth Colt (Box 5)
  - Sigourney, L.H. to Hetty B. Hart (Box 5)
  - Sigourney, L.H. to Samuel Colt (Box 5)
  - Sigourney, Lydia assorted correspondence (Box 5)
  - Smith, Ichabod - Accounts (William Hart and others), 1790s (Box 5)
  - Stapley, Seth P. (Box 5)
  - Stedman, Edmund C. (Box 5)
  - Stone, Eliza T. (Box 5)
  - Toucey, Catherine (Box 5)
  - Toucey, Isaac, "The Navy in 1860-1861" (Box 5)
  - Toucey, Isaac, Estate (Box 5)
  - Tuthill, Mrs. L. "Poem in Memoriam: Edward Jarvis", 1842 (Box 6)
  - Tyler, Frederick, Estate (Box 6)
  - Victoria (Queen of England) to George Peabody (Box 6)
  - Wallace, Lew to Elizabeth Colt, 1882 (Box 6)
  - Ward, Sam (Box 6)
  - "Wethered, Samuel" to Hetty J. James (Beach) regarding Samuel Colt (Box 6)
  - Whitney, Stephen Estate (Box 6)
  - Day, William, correspondence (Box 6)
  - DeGroot Family
    - Franny (Box 6)
    - Henry (and wife) correspondence (Box 6)
    - William, 1825-1898 (Box 6)
    - William, passport (Box 6)
  - Dennis, S.A. to Richard Jarvis, 1881 (Box 6)
  - Dewey, George to C.L.F. Robinson (Box 6)
  - Dyer, H.A. (Artist?) (Box 6)
  - Earth Closet Co. (Hartford, CT), 1869 (Box 6)
  - Eastman, G.C.V., 1837 (Box 6)
  - Elliott, Maude Howe to Mrs. C.L.F. Robinson (Box 6)
  - Everets, William Maxwell, 1878 (Box 6)
  - Fiske, John, 1885 (Box 6)
  - Family gifts to Fitzgerald at emptying of Armsmear (Box 6)
  - Flagg, Charles Noel (Box 6)
  - Franklin, W.B. (Box 6)
  - Frost, Charles R. (estate) (Box 6)
  - Frost, Charles Leonard, misc. material (Box 6)
  - Frost, RR disclaimer (Box 6)
  - Grace Church (Saybrook Conn.) (Box 6)
  - Granger, G. (Box 6)
  - Gray, William Crane (Box 6)
  - Grenfell, Wilfred (Box 6)
  - Hancock, Winfield Scott, autograph (Box 6)
  - Hart, Elizabeth, estate and inventory (Box 6)
  - Hart, Elizabeth, insurance policy (Box 6)
  - Hart, Elizabeth, calling card printing plate (Box 6)
  - Hart, Elizabeth, letter from Reverend Burgess, Pastor (Box 6)
  - Hart, Hetty Buckingham (1800-1876), In memoriam (Box 6)
  - Hart, Hetty, correspondence (Box 6)
  - Hart, Joseph (1755-1800?), business card (Box 6)
  - Henshaw, Caroline (Mlle. Leicester) and Samuel Colt Jr., merchant's bills, Europe, 1850s (Box 6)
  - Sheffield, Amelia Hotchkiss (1827-?) (Box 6)
  - Hubbard, Elijah H. (Box 6)
  - Hull, Amelia Hart (Box 6)
  - Jarvis Family
    - Abraham (Box 6)
    - Elizabeth Miller Hart, correspondence (Box 6)
    - Elizabeth Miller Hart (Box 6)
    - John S. (1837-1866) death notice (Box 6)
    - Leonard (Box 6)
    - Richard William Hart (1829-1903) (Box 6)
    - Richard W. H. correspondence (Box 6)
    - Samuel Farmar (Box 6)
    - William (Box 6)
  - Kellogg, George (Box 6)
  - LaFarge, Bancel (Box 7)
  - LaTourette, Nancy (Box 7)
  - Lawton, Ida May Frost (Robinson) estate (Box 7)
  - Mabury, F.F. (Box 7)
  - Mallory, William L., sale of land in Sheffield, Ohio (Box 7)
  - Miller, Elizabeth, copy of will, 1804 (Box 7)
  - Mills, Isaac, correspondence (Box 7)
  - Morgan, E.D. (Governor of New York) (Box 7)
  - Mount Vernon Ladies' Association of the Union (Box 7)
  - Nichols, Cyprian (1773-1853), estate (Box 7)
  - Osborn, George L. (Box 7)
  - Pershing, John J. to Mrs C.L.F. Robinson (Box 7)
  - Read, Thomas Buchanan (Box 7)
  - Richards, Timothy P. (Box 7)
  - Robinson Family
    - Caldwell Colt correspondence (Box 7)
    - Caldwell Colt, writing, 1909-1916 (Box 7)
    - Caldwell Colt, military service record, tributes, commendations (Box 7)
    - Caldwell Colt, newspaper clipping In Memoriam and other related clippings (Box 7)
    - Caldwell Colt, memorabilia (Box 7)
    - Caldwell Colt, ephemera regarding World War I service (Box 7)
    - Caldwell Colt, biographical, personal history, copies of news reports (Box 8)
    - Caldwell Colt, ephemera relating to war service (Box 8)
    - Charles, (1816-?) (Box 8)
    - Daniel Chapman (1803-1878) (Box 8)
    - Charles Leonard Frost correspondence (Box 8)
    - Charles Leonard Frost, correspondence letters to his mother (Box 8)
    - Mrs. C.L.F. Robinson correspondence (Box 8)
  - Aldrich, Mrs. Thomas B. (Box 8)
  - Anthony, Henry B. (Box 8)
  - Barney, Hiram (Box 8)
  - Bailey, Vernon (Box 8)
  - Beach, Cyprian Nichols (1828-1887)
    - Correspondence, 1886, undated; 2 (Box 8)
    - Letters from Hetty Haut Jarvis (Beach) (Box 8)
    - Correspondence regarding Texas and New Orleans Railroad, 1870s (Box 8)
    - Letter from E.D. Morgan (Box 9)
    - Correspondence from Lizzie (E.H.J.B. Robinson) (Box 9)
    - Passport (Box 9)
    - Receipt for objects, 1866-1872 (Box 9)
    - Business and Cheques (Box 9)
    - Death Notices, etc. (Box 9)
    - Estate (Box 9)
    - Beach, Hettie Jarvis
      - Correspondence, 4 (Box 9)
      - Letters from Lizzie (E.H.J.B.) Robinson (Box 9)
      - From Lydia Sigourney regarding fall of CT Charter Oak (news clipping, poem, letter), 1856 (Box 9)
      - Letter from E.D. Morgan, 1879 (Box 9)
      - Accounts (Box 9)
      - Letters of congratulation regarding her upcoming wedding and some regrets, unable to attend, 1867 (Box 9)
      - "Martha Washington Tea Party" (Box 9)
      - Passport, 1890 (Box 9)
      - Death Notice Oct. 31, 1898 (Box 9)
  - Beach, J.W., correspondence (Box 9)
  - Beach, Maria Nichols, toucey letters, 1799-1845 (Box 9)
  - Brown, Charles S. (Box 10)
  - Bull, Caleb (Box 10)
  - Chase, Salmon P., to Hiram Barney, 1862 (Box 10)
  - Clark, George H. (Box 10)
  - Cleveland, Frances S. (secretary), 1887 (Box 10)
  - Cleveland, Grover and Frances F., signatures on a card (Box 10)
  - Cleveland, Grover letter to Elizabeth Colt, 1889 February 12 (Box 10)
  - Colt, Caldwell Hart, correspondence, 2 (Box 10)
  - Colt, Elizabeth Hart Jarvis
    - Receiving card on the occasion of wedding E.H.J.B. and C.L.F.R. (Box 10)
    - Calling card, "At Homes," etc. (Box 10)
    - Invitation to Hettie H.J. Beach wedding, 1867 (Box 10)
    - Invitation to Caldwell Colt's 21st birthday party, 1879 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, 1858-1879 (Box 10)
    - Letter regarding sale of yacht Oreole, 1894 (Box 10)
    - Church, Frederick E., letter from (Box 10)
    - Martha Washington Tea Party, 1875 (Box 10)
    - Form letter to applicants for charity, 1869 (Box 10)
    - Letters with her son Caldwell Hart Colt and his man L. Bradley from a trip across the U.S., 1875 (Box 10)
    - Letters of remembrance (Box 10)
    - Correspondence from E.H.J.B. Robinson, 1900-1902 (Box 10)
    - Letter from Frederick Church, 1866 (Box 10)
    - Letter from Chase, Salmon P., after 1864 (Box 10)
    - Birthday poem for Lizzie's 5th, 1874 (Box 10)
    - Receipt for Hetty B. Hart funeral expenses, 1876 (Box 10)
    - Business papers etc., 1861 (Box 10)
    - Payroll, 1871 (Box 10)
    - Probate certificate as guardian to Caldwell H Colt, 1868 (Box 10)
    - Receipts delinquent land tax, Iowa, 1877-1878 (Box 10)
    - Will, in unbound and unsewn signatures, 1902 (Box 10)
    - In Memoriam, reprinted from Parish of Good Shepherd, 1905; 2 (Box 10)
    - Clipping from 'Hartford Courant' - "Gifts from Mrs. Colt", 1905 December 23 (Box 11)
    - Received from estate of J.M. Jarvis, 1881 July 15 (Box 11)
    - Newspaper regarding gift of land to city of Hartford and statue of Col. Colt, 1905 November 2 (Box 11)
    - Estate, 1911 (Box 11)
    - Card List (Box 11)
    - Hartford Courant Chicago Tribune (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, 1880-1905, undated; 2 (Box 11)
  - Colt, Henrietta Selden, lines written on the death of L.H. Sigourney, 1862 (Box 11)
  - Colt, J.R., correspondence, 1855 (Box 11)
  - Colt, Samuel Jarvis, 1857 (Box 11)
  - Stockholders in Colt Patent Firearms (Box 11)
  - Corrigan, M.A. Right Rev. (Box 11)
  - Cushman, Elizabeth Sanderson (died October 4, 1936), obituary and letter (Box 11)
  - Robinson family Frank Tracey, sheet music (Box 12)
  - Sigourney, L.H. tribute to Mt. Vernon, 1858 February 22 (Box 12)
  - Robinson Family
    - Caldwell Colt, New Testament (Box 11)
    - Elizabeth H.J. Beach diary, 1907-1919 (Box 11)
    - Elizabeth H.J. (Mrs. C.L.F.) travelogue, 1900 (Box 11)
    - Elizabeth H.J.B. date book, address book, 1900 June-July (Box 11)
    - Elizabeth H.J.B. travelogue (Box 11)
    - Elizabeth H.J.B. travelogue, year on the 'Norseman', 1906 (Box 11)
    - Elizabeth, H.J.B. address book (Box 11)
    - Two catalogs of the Art Work of S. Arlent Edwards (Mezzotints has signature of "from J. Percy Sabin) (Fine Prints includes a letter "Dear Mrs. Robinson" April 6 '15 from J. Percy Sabin regarding sale of prints) (Box 11)
    - Unidentified diaries, address books, and travelogues, 1894, undated; 2 (Box 13)
    - Gaylord family history, 1906-1914, undated (Box 13)
    - Genealogy, 1913, undated; 4 (Box 13)
    - Application Papers of C.L.F. Robinson for the Order of Descendants of Colonial Governors (Box 13)
    - Application Paper of E.H.J. Robinson, All Societies (Box 14)
    - Genealogical Papers, Maternal Line of E.H.J. Robinson (Box 14)
    - An Illustrated Catalogue of Some of the Heirlooms Owned by Families in Connecticut, with manuscript annotations (Box 14)
    - Robinson, Charles L. Frost Correspondence and other with Kaiser regarding racing, 1903-1904 (Box 14)
    - Robinson, C.L.F., Montana Ore Mines correspondence, 1904 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence and letters of introduction, circumnavigation, 1906-1907 (Box 14)
    - Norseman - trip round the world, ship's log, 1906 (Box 14)
    - Letters regarding disputed payments for 'Norseman', 1908-1909 (Box 14)
    - Titanic related letters, 1912 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence regarding Norseman (Box 15)
    - Concerning Dos Cabezas Mining Co. (Box 15)
    - Regarding application for diplomatic appointment, 1906 (Box 15)
    - Biographical material (Box 15)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 15)
    - Charles L. F. Robinson assorted calling cards (Box 15)
    - Books & Prints (receipts & notes) (Box 15)
    - Rare book receipts (Box 15)
    - Two copies of Catalog of Library of the Late C.L.F. Robinson, the Anderson Gallery, 1917 (Box 15)
    - Marriage certificate of C.L.F. Robinson and Elizabeth H.J. Robinson, with wills, 1896, 1907 (Box 15)
    - Robinson, Hayden and Co. (Box 15)
  - Elizabeth Hart Jarvis Beach
    - Letters to her on her first (?) birthday, 1870 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1869-1918, undated; 1 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1869-1918, undated; 5 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence regarding family heirlooms, 1931 January 9 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence from C.L.F. Robinson (Box 17)
  - U.S. War Dept. General Orders No 8 1855, "Manual for Colt's Revolver" (Box 17)
  - United States Magazine IV:3 "Repeating Firearms" p. [221]-249, 1857 March (Box 17)
  - U.S. Secretary of War letter on Colt's Submarine Battery House, 1845 December 27 (Box 17)
  - "Testimonials on the Usefulness of Colt's Repeating Fire Arms from Europeans Journals" (Hartford Times Office Print, 1852) (Box 17)
  - The Artizan XVI, no. CXCI "Colt's New Model Repeating Rifle" p. 285-6 254- diagram, 1858 December 1 (Box 17)
  - Clippings from Samuel Colt's Scrapbook, 2 (Box 17)
  - Samuel Colt's Scrapbook (Box 17)
  - The Calendar, No 889 Sigourney's Elegies of Samuel and Henrietta Colt, p. 1, 1862 January 25 (Box 18)
  - Vallencillo Silver Mining Co. to Samuel Colt, 1858 (Box 18)
  - Dix, John Ross "Poetry and Pistols" mounted clippings, 1859 (Box 18)
  - Broadside Poetry American, 1830s or 1840s (Box 18)
  - Revolutionary war correspondence, 1789-1799 (Box 18)
  - Cyprian Nicols Beach passport, 1882 (Box 18)
  - List of Cyprian Nicols books, 1859 March (Box 18)
  - Beach, E.H. diary from Spain, 1882 (Box 18)
  - Colt, E.H.S. travelogue, 1882-1883; 5 (Box 18)
  - Colt, E.H.S. list of books to read, 1884 (Box 19)
  - Colt, E.H.S. marriage vows, 1896 (Box 19)
  - Colt, E.H.S. address book (Box 19)
  - Colt, E.H.S. ledger, 1870s (Box 19)
  - Robinson, C.L.F. autograph list of inventory of 1161 Prospect St., West Hartford, 1828 (Box 19)
  - Robinson, C.L.F. inventory of letters, prints, and naval engagements, 1907 (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper articles, 1893 (Box 20)
  - Travel and other journals and related material, 1858-1919, undated (Box 20)
  - Travel and other journals and related material, 1858-1919, undated (Box 21)
  - Travel and other journals and related material, 1858-1919, undated (Box 22)
  - Travel and other journals and related material, 1858-1919, undated (Box 23)
  - Diary of H. Beach, undated (Box 24)
  - Bible owned and signed by Cyprian Nichols (Box 24)
  - Saybrook old property maps and surveys, 1847 (Box 24)
  - Photographs, 3 (Box 24)
  - Photographs, 7 (Box 25)